<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: IT | Petes Stuff]]></title>
  <link href="http://peetjthinkful.github.io/blog/categories/it/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://peetjthinkful.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-05-24T20:19:58+10:00</updated>
  <id>http://peetjthinkful.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Pete Januarius]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Backups, backups and more backups]]></title>
    <link href="http://peetjthinkful.github.io/blog/2014/11/08/backups-backups/"/>
    <updated>2014-11-08T19:07:00+11:00</updated>
    <id>http://peetjthinkful.github.io/blog/2014/11/08/backups-backups</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>You would&rsquo;ve thought that I had learnt my lesson when it comes to backing up my files. I think I  must have helped dozens of friends over the years who had lost a critical file and hadn&rsquo;t made a backup. Well I managed to do exactly the same thing at work the other day.</p>

<p>I was working in <a href="http://www.sublimetext.com/">Sublime Text 3</a> on Windows and managed to lose a mornings work &ndash; Doh! I quickly realised that I had no local history and hadn&rsquo;t committed to any repository for a while. Hmmmm&hellip; what to do! Well nothing actually, I just had to write all the code again !!!</p>

<p>I did, however find a nice local history plugin for Sublime Text which is really the point of this post. No more troubles!</p>

<p><a href="https://github.com/vishr/local-history">Local History</a> is a Sublime Text (2 &amp; 3) plugin for maintaining local history of files. [backup | open | compare | incremental diff].</p>

<p>It helps if you have the <a href="https://sublime.wbond.net/">package installer</a> for ST. In this case just type &lsquo;Local History&rsquo; at the install package prompt and there you go.</p>

<p>Once installed, I just configured the user settings to have a <code>history_retention</code> of 90 days:</p>

<pre><code>{
  "history_retention": 90, // in days
}
</code></pre>

<p>Seems to work really well!</p>

<p>Another backup solution that I have signed up for is <a href="https://www.zipcloud.com/planprice-information">ZipCloud</a>. I&rsquo;ve included a link to the pricing page as it is difficult to find. You only get a few Gig if you get the free plan so I upgraded to the Premium Plan and am paying about 7 USD per month.</p>

<p>The reason I needed it is that I am upgrading my Mac to Yosemite and don&rsquo;t really have an adequate backup solution. After running the backup client for about 2 weeks (yes really!), I finally backed up everything. It was quite impressive as I just had to pause it everytime I needed to &ndash; other than that I ran it constantly.</p>

<p>It is finally done and I can now upgrade. Yay!</p>

<p><img src="../images/backup.gif" title="Backups, backups" alt="Backups by ahajokes.com" /></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
